A Guide to the Alfred Ezra Mirsky papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA131
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, 1929 1942-1974; 2
  - Wi-Wy (Box 15)
    - Wilkins, M.H.F., 8 letters
      Includes Wilkins paper and photos.
    - Wilkinson, Endymion, 4 letters
    - Williams, Carrol M. Concerning Hewson Swift nomination to NAS, 3 letters
    - Williams, Janet, 1 letter
    - Williams, M., 2 letters
    - Willier, B.H., 1 letter
    - Wilson, Jean D. University of Texas address, planned to attend but cancelled (wife's illness), 1966 November 30; 4 letters
    - Wilson, Paul T., 6 letters
    - Wilt, Fred, 2 letters
    - Windham, I., 2 letters
    - Winnick, Theodore. Item on job inquiry for P.R. Adiga, 5 letters
    - Winzler, Richard J., 2 letters
    - Wishny, J., 2 letters
    - Wistar Institute Press, 1 letter
    - Witkin, Evelyn M., 2 letters
    - Wixom, Charles W., 1 letter
    - Woernley, D.L., 2 letters
    - Wohl, Sonia, 1 letter
    - Wolk, Peter. RU graduate student, 6 letters
      Includes ms for Ph.D presentation.
    - Woolley, D. Woolley comments on K. Radha thesis, 1 letter
    - Work, T.S., 7 letters
      Includes comments on published paper.
    - Worthington Biochemical Corp., 1 letter
    - Wyatt, G.R. Yale address, 1964 February 19; 3 letters
    - Wyatt, H.V., 2 letters
    - Wyckoff, W.G. Concerning RI film library, 1 letter
    - Wyman, Jeffries, 3 letters
    - Wynn, Willard, 2 letters
  - Y-Z (Box 15)
    - Yaffee, David, 2 letters
    - Yagi, Kunio, 2 letters
    - Yahraes, Herbert, 1 letter
    - Yam, Ana, 2 letters
    - Yamado, Tuneo.; Primarily deals with financial support for Osawa, 1952-1964; 39 letters
    - Yasuzami, G., 1 letter
    - Yeda, (no initial), 1 letter
    - Young, Donald R., 1 letter
    - Young, Francis A., 1 letter
    - Zamenhof, Stephen. Comments on published book, 1 letter
    - Zamecnik, Paul. Polio Foundation Conference, 1957 January; 1 letter
    - Zaunick, Rudolph. Zbarsky, I.B. (13), 1960-1970; 2 letters
    - Zeuthen, Erik. Note on Heinz Holter 70th birthday, 4 letters
    - Zirkin, Barry R., 3 letters
      Includes vitae.
- RU Administration, Subject Files, 3
  - Academic Council, 1957 (Box 16)
    Plan of advisor for each student and mechanics established in 1957.
  - Correspondence, 1958-1972 (Box 16)
    Miscellaneous correspondence comprised of administration announcements dealing with seminars, student guides, catalog information and committee reports. Primarily duplicated material.
  - Course Material, 1960-1962; 5 folders (Box 16)
    Course material was arranged for RU students which consisted of orientation lectures, seminars and special reading lists. A.E. Mirsky was chairman.
    - Cell Biology Seminars, 2 folders
      Correspondence; lectures; outlines; bibliography.
    - Differentiation and Development Seminars Reading lists for lectures 1-6
    - Archeology correspondence; and outline, 1965-1967
    - Developmental Biology Reading Program, 1966-1968
      Correspondence; reading lists; student reports.
    - Student Program Personal or committee opinions on work progress, theses and programming of students (Box 16)
      - Paul R. Burgess
      - Robert D. Campo
      - Eric H. Davidson
      - David L. Eaker
      - Mr. Edmundson
      - Chandler Fulton
      - Johns Hopkins
      - Arthur Karlin
      - Robert Krug
      - John J. Marchalonis
      - Howard Rasmussen
      - Dr. Rizak
      - Harold Simon
      - Roger Thies
      - J.W. Vanable
      - E. Frederick Wheelock
      - Peter Wolk
      - Donald A. Young
  - Campus Clubs (Box 16)
    - Faculty and Student Club Financial statements; membership items; annual report
    - Student Journal Club Organized by AE Mirsky in November 1957, 1957 November
  - Housing (Box 16)
  - Library, 1951-1971 (Box 16)
    Misc correspondence including material on renovations; library use; budget; gift of Radl books; student proposals and comments on proposals; exhibit of botanical books.
  - Press; Purchasing, 1948-1967 (Box 16)
  - Power House (Box 16)
    Scope and Contents
    Copy of letter to George Karda who was attacked in student newspaper.
  - Accounting Records, 6 boxes and a package
    Correspondence dealing with grants, laboratory expenditures, student accounts, special activities; blue slips; charge slips; shop orders; purchase orders; monthly financial statements; budget expenditure statements. Some purchase orders for Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences filed with mss and some purchase orders for equipment filed under company name.
    Arranged in chronological order and within each month in accounting dept designated account numbers and categories of: (equipment, consumable supplies, travel, other expenses and publication costs) Not complete in every instance. Beginning with July 1970 accounting system changed to print out sheets (monthly financial statements).
    - NIH Grants, 4 folders (Box 17)
      Correspondence; financial with budget expenditure statements; blue with charge slips.
      - 1966 December-1967 March (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - 1967 April-August (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - 1967 September-1968 August (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - 1967 December-1968 March (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - NIH Grants, 5 folders (Box 18)
      - 1968 April-May (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - 1968 June-1969 January (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - 1968 December-1969 June (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - 1969 July-1970 January (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - 1969 December-1972 November (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Seminars, 3 folders (Box 19)
      - Correspondence; budget expenditure statements; vouchers; charge slips
      - Archeology Seminars, 1965 December-1969 June (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Cell Biology Seminars, 1963 August-1969 June (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Differentiation and Development Seminars, 1965 July-1970 February (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - New York Heart Assoc Grant
      - Monthly financial and budget expenditure statements; paid purchase orders, 1969 August-1974 February
      - Bert Silverman Institutional Allowance Paid purchase orders and travel voucher, 1971 February-1972 November
      - Mirsky/Dole NIH Grant Paid purchase orders, 1973 October-1974 June
    - Student Accounts, 7 folders (Box 20)
      1 memo concerning Finch; budget expenditure statements; blue slips; charge slips; various services charge slips.
      - Students Account (Box 20, Folder 1)
        - (1) Tidwell
        - (2) Kleinsmith
        - (3) Finch
        - 1966 August-1967 August
      - Student Account (Finch), 3 folders (Box 20)
        - 1967 August-1968 July (Box 20, Folder 2)
        - 1967 September-1968 October (Box 20, Folder 3)
        - 1968 July-1969 October (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Students Account, 3 folders (Box 20)
        - 1967 July-December (Box 20, Folder 5)
        - 1968 January-March (Box 20, Folder 6)
        - 1968 April-June (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Laboratory Accounts, 9 folders (Box 21)
      Monthly budget expenditure statements; blue slips; charge slips; from Aug 1969 thru Nov 1969 charge slips transferred from NY Heart Assoc Grant to Laboratory Account with summary of entire transfer; 2 items correspondence; in July 1970 accounting system changed to monthly print out sheets (financial statements).
      Paid purchase orders arranged in chronological order in month paid.
      - 1966 November-1969 June (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - 1969 July-1970 March (partial) (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - 1970 March (partial) (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - 1970 March (partial) (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - 1970 April-June (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - 1970 July-1971 October (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - 1971 November-1972 August (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - 1972 September-1973 May (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - 1973 June-1974 June (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Telephone Bills (Box 22)
      - 1969 July-1974 June
      - Telephone bills charged to Laboratory Account; not a bill for every month. Lack may indicate no charges for month
    - Dry Ice Distribution, 1966 November-1968 April (Box 22)
      Blue slips only.
    - Miscellanea Accounts (Mirsky, Finch, Allfrey, Davidson), 1965 November-1968 October (Box 22)
      Blue slips; shop orders; charge slips; budget expenditure statements.
      Arranged in chronological order within account number.
    - Mirsky/Allfrey Account? (No internal evidence as to what type of account) (grant or otherwise?), 1966 November-1968 January (Box 22)
    - Print out sheets (Monthly financial statements), 1970 July-1974 June (Package 22a)
  - Christmas Lectures, 1958-1974 (Box 23)
    (See Boxes 44 and 45 for lectures and film).
    - History-Retrospective review; photographs; posters; News and Notes, 1974 December (Box 23)
    - Administrative Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 23)
      Arrangements on grants, reports, speakers invitations.
      - 1958-1963
      - 1964-1974
    - Correspondence with schools and students, 1959-1974 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence with Anita Oser, 1965-1970 (Box 23)
    - Anita Oser Prize Essays, 1967 (Box 23)
    - Accounts, 1963-1974 (Box 23)
    - Press Article 1959; Photographs of Christmas Lectures, 1959 1961 1962 1963 1964 1965 (Box 23)
    - Posters and tickets Not complete (Box 23)
    - The Alfred E. Mirsky Christmas Lectures On Science. Renamed so for Dec 1974 lectures in honor of series founder, Alfred E. Mirsky Procedures for invitations, ticket requests and distribution (Box 24)
    - Samples of procedure and school mailings (Box 24)
    - Schools attendance and ushers (Box 24)
    - Student lists requesting tickets to lectures received from individual schools (Box 24)
      Arranged in alphabetical order by school.
  - Grants (Box 25)
    - NIH Proposals, 1956-1965 1965-1972
    - NIH Award notices, 1956-1973
    - NIH Expenditures; Progress Reports Progress reports: June 1958-June 1959; Dec 1956-Jan 1961; 1963?; 1964 and 1966-1967 publications; 1973 final report
    - NIH Correspondence, 1956-1974
      Engineer's sketch S/S water tank; evaluations for NIH of proposals.
    - Life Insurance Medical Research Fund Proposal for Caleb Finch, 1969 July 1-1974 June 30
      NY Heart Assoc Grant.
    - Grant proposal; correspondence
  - Administrative matters dealing with Alfred E. Mirsky Laboratory (Box 26)
    - Budgets
      Includes some correspondence.
      - 1950/1951-1970/1971, 1950-1971
      - Lacks 1951/1952; 1952/1953; 1954/1955; 1968/1969
      - Proposal only, 1969-1970
    - Efforts Reports (time spent on various activities)
      - Vincent Allfrey, 1967-1968
      - Marco Crippa Jan 1968 only, 1968 January
      - A.E. Mirsky, 1967-1971
      - Bert Silverman, 1972-1974
    - Laboratory Equipment, 2 folders
      Arranged in alphabetical order A-N; P-Z.
      - Quotations; purchase orders; 1970 inventory
      - hazardous chemicals inventory, 1971
    - Miscellaneous
      Journal subscriptions, salaries and vacations for non-faculty personnel.
  - Student Ph.D Theses and Davidson, Eric H. book Theses
    - Bachvarova, Rosemary F., 1966 (Box 27)
    - Davidson, Eric H., 1963 (Box 27)
    - Finch, Caleb E. (bound), 1969 (Box 27)
    - Kleinsmith, Lewis J., 1968 (Box 27)
    - McEwen, Bruce S., 1963 (Box 27)
    - Tidwell, James T., 1967 (Box 28)
    - Davidson, Eric H. working ms of book Gene Activity in Animal Development; published title varies: Gene Activity in Early Development Academic Press; dedicated to Alfred E. Mirsky, 1968 (Box 28)
- Manuscript materials, 4
  Include Annual Scientific reports; subject collections of special interest; working papers and some laboratory notes in some cases and some multiple corrected drafts. Listed with publication information where possible. Some not A.E. Mirsky.
  - Annual Scientific Reports, 1945-1974 (Box 29)
    3 folders Lacking 1952; 1962-1968; 1969-1970 1947 has biography of H. Ris 1973/1974 was written by Bert Silverman.
    - 1945-1950
    - 1951-1955
    - 1956-1974
  - Materials dealing with transformation of pneumococci, DNA and Eugenics, 8 folders (Box 29)
    - Avery, Oswald Theodore, 2 folders
      - Collection of items: correspondence and articles by R. Dubos, Joshua Lederberg, Jack S. Cohen dealing with Avery work on the transformation of pneumococcus (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Consists of copies of Avery annual reports 1928-1954 and copies of letters from Avery (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Callan, H.G.
      Correspondence with H.G. Callan enclosing questionning note on Callan paper. Note never published.
    - Darlington, C.D. exchange, 1971 August
      Op-Ed article and A.E. Mirsky Letter to Editor, New York Times.
    - Dental Caries-Heritability, 1927-1971
      Collection of photocopied papers.
    - Eugenics
      - Bibliography
      - L.C. Dunn "The Transformation of Biology: A Geneticist's Viewpoint"
      - F. Seitz "Human Genetics and Urban Slums" NAS Council statement
    - Stent, Gunther S.
      Review article on DNA for Daedalus (draft) with A.E. Mirsky prepublication comments.
    - Stern, Curt
      A.E. Mirsky prepublication comments for Daedalus on Curt Stern "The Continuity of Genetics" Includes other Stern reprints and Stern review of Darlington "Facts of Life".
  - Miscellaneous; not A.E. Mirsky; not clearly identified
    - A.E. Mirsky notes, outlines, reviews (Box 30)
      Various notes (few dated) includes outline with working materials of "The Role of the Nucleus in Differentiation"; some tentative notes and outlines for talks; some additional notes not identified by date or subject.
    - A.E. Mirsky and L. Pauling. On the structure of native, denatured and coagulated proteins, 1936 (Box 30)
      PNAS 22, 439-447. Typescript draft.
    - A.E. Mirsky and A.W. Pollister. Nucleoproteins of cell nuclei, 1942 (Box 30)
      PNAS 28, 344-352.
      Typescript draft with photographs of plates.
    - A.W. Pollister and A.E. Mirsky. Preparation of a nucleohistone from mammalian organs, and direct demonstration of its nuclear origin. Genetics 27, 160-161 (Abstract), 1942; Typescript draft (Box 30)
    - A.E. Mirsky and A.W. Pollister. Fibrous nucleoproteins of chromatin, 1943 (Box 30)
      Biol Symp X, 247-260. Photographs of figures.
    - A.E. Mirsky and A.W. Pollister. The nucleoprotamine of the trout sperm, 1946 (Box 30)
      JGP 30, 101-116.
      Typescript drafts with corrections, reprint, figures and photographs of plates, working materials.
    - A.E. Mirsky and A.W. Pollister Chromosin, a desoxyribose nucleoprotein complex of the cell nucleus, 1946 (Box 30)
      JGP 30, 117-148.
      Typescript drafts with corrections and figures.
    - A.E. Mirsky and A.W. Pollister Some properties of histones, 194? (Box 30)
      (no publication information).
      Typescript draft.
    - I. Snapper, A.E. Mirsky, H. Ris, B. Schneid and M. Rosenthal, 1947 (Box 30)
      Development of inclusion bodies containing ribose nucleic acid in myeloma cells after injections of stilbamidine. Determination of stilbamidine in myeloma tissue.
      Blood 2, 311-322.
      Typescript draft of part of discussion.
    - A.E. Mirsky and H. Ris Isolated chromosomes, 1947 (Box 30)
      JGP 31, 1-6.
      Typescript drafts with-corrections.
    - A.E. Mirsky and H. Ris, 1949 (Box 30)
      Variable and constant components of chromosomes.
      Nature 163, 666-667.
    - H. Ris and A.E. Mirsky. The state of the chromosomes in the interphase nucleus, 1949 (Box 30)
      JGP 32, 499-502.
      Photographs of figures.
    - H. Ris and A.E. Mirsky. Quantitative cytochemical determination of desoxyribonucleic acid with the Feulgen nucleal reaction, 1949 (Box 30)
      JGP 33, 125-146.
    - D.D. Mark and H. Ris (Not A.E. Mirsky) A comparison of desoxyribonucleic content in certain nuclei of normal liver and liver tumors. (Submitted to Proc Soc Exp Biol Med), circa 1949; Typescript draft (Box 30)
    - L. Cunningham, A. Clark Griffin and J. Murray Luck Polypoidy and cancer. The desoxypentosenucleic acid content of nuclei of normal, precancerous and neoplastic rat tissue. A.E. Mirsky advisor on this investigation, 1950 (Box 30)
      (See Laboratory Notes Box 48 Rooster Sperm).
      JGP 34, 59-63.
    - N.B. Kurnick Methyl green pyronin. I. Basis of selective staining of nucleic acids, 1950 (Box 30)
      This is Part I of paper by N.B. Kurnick only Typescript drafts with corrections; 1 item correspondence from Kurnick to Mirsky [Part II. A.E. Mirsky and N.B. Kurnick co-authors, II. Stoichiometry of reaction with nucleic acids. No typescript draft of part II].
      JGP 33, 243-274.
    - A.E. Mirsky, A.W. Pollister, H. Ris Histones and protamines V., 1950? (Box 30)
      npi (no publication information).
    - A.E. Mirsky holograph draft (Box 30)
    - V.G. Allfrey, A.E. Mirsky and H. Stern Differentiation of the cell nucleus, 1950 (Box 31)
      Internal evidence indicates ms submitted to JGP, Aug 1950.
      Typescript drafts (partially handwritten by A.E. Mirsky) with corrections.
    - Jane Oppenheimer (Rockefeller Foundation Fellow 1950-1951) (Box 31)
      first report; correspondence with R. Dubos; 4 preliminary reports; final report "Science and The Private Mind" submitted as RF Fellow. A.E. Mirsky along with R. Dubos, one of original advisors; includes Oppenheimer correspondence with Mirsky.
    - A.E. Mirsky and H. Ris. The desoxyribonucleic acid content of animal cells and its evolutionary significance, 1951 (Box 31)
      JGP 34, 451-462.
      Typescript and handwritten drafts with corrections.
    - A.E. Mirsky and H. Ris. The composition and structure of isolated chromosomes, 1951 (Box 31)
      JGP 34, 475-492.
      Typescript and handwritten drafts with corrections; galley proofs.
    - H. Ris and A.E. Mirsky Isolated chromosomes, 1951 (Box 31)
      Exptl Cell Res 2, 263-267.
      Typescript drafts with corrections; correspondence from Ris to Mirsky; Runnstrøm to Ris.
    - A.E. Mirsky. "Some chemical aspects of the cell nucleus", 1951 (Box 31)
      Genetics in the 20th Century, L.C. Dunn (Ed.) pp.127-153.
      Typescript drafts with corrections; galley proof; 1 handwritten letter from Mirsky to Allfrey.
    - H. Stern, V.G. Allfrey, A.E. Mirsky and H. Saetren Some enzymes of isolated nuclei, 1952 (Box 31)
      JGP 35, 559-578.
      Negatives of tables.
    - M.M. Daly, V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. Uptake of glycine-N15 by components of cell nuclei, 1952 (Box 31)
      JGP 36, 173-179.
      Typescript drafts with corrections and addition; galley proof.
    - H. Stern and A.E. Mirsky. The isolation of wheat germ nuclei and some aspects of their glycolytic metabolism, 1952 (Box 31)
      JGP 36, 181-200.
      Typescript draft and negatives of tables and figure.
    - V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. Some aspects of the desoxyribonuclease activities of animal tissues, 1952 (Box 31)
      JGP 36, 227-241.
    - M.M. Daly and A.E. Mirsky Formation of protein in the pancreas, 1952 (Box 31)
      JGP 36, 243-254.
      Working draft.
    - A.E. Mirsky. The chemistry of heredity, 1953 (Box 32)
      Scientific American 188, 47-57.
      Typescript drafts; galley proofs of photographs with explanation sheet for each photo (see A.H. Sparrow folder in Box 62; several Sparrow photographs used for this article).
    - A.E. Mirsky. Book review of "Cytochemistry. A Critical Approach" by J.F. Danielli, 1953 (Box 32)
      American Naturalist 87, 164-165 Photocopy of review This review unsigned but internal evidence indicates A.E. Mirsky reviewed this book (see Box 12 correspondence with Rothschild).
    - V.G. Allfrey, M.M. Daly and A.E. Mirsky Synthesis of protein in the pancreas. II. The role of ribonucleoprotein in protein synthesis, 1953 (Box 32)
      JGP 37, 157-175.
      Galley proof; typescript and handwritten drafts.
    - H. Stern and A.E. Mirsky. Soluble enzymes of nuclei isolated in sucrose and non-aqueous media, a comparative study, 1953 (Box 32)
      JGP 37, 177-187.
      Galley proof; typescript draft with corrections.
    - A.E. Mirsky and H. Stern Genetics and cell physiology in studies of the cell nucleus, 1953? (Box 32)
    - A.E. Mirsky. Book review of "The Facts of Life" by CD. Darlington, 1954 (Box 32)
      Scientific American 190, 92-94.
      Magazine copy; typescript and handwritten drafts.
    - V.G. Allfrey. Amino acid incorporation by isolated thymus nuclei. I. The role of desoxyribonucleic acid in protein synthesis, 1954 (Box 32)
      PNAS 40, 881-885.
      Typescript drafts.
    - V.G. Allfrey, A.E. Mirsky and H. Stern. The chemistry of the cell nucleus. (chapter in book), 1955; 3 folders (Box 32)
      Advances in Enzymology Vol XI, F.F. Nord (ed.).
      - Correspondence; galley proof; printer's copy with corrections and working tables (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence; corrected galley proof; typescript draft with corrections (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Typescript drafts of Allfrey Part II (Box 32, Folder 3)
        Working materials; laboratory notes kept in order in which found.
    - A.E. Mirsky. Book review of "My Life with The Microbes" by Selman A. Waksman, 1955 (Box 33)
      The Nation, Jan 22, 78.
      Galley proof; typescript drafts; photocopy of magazine printing.
    - M.M. Daly and A.E. Mirsky. Histones with high lysine content, 1955 (Box 33)
      JGP 38, 405-413.
      Galley proof; typescript and handwritten drafts with corrections.
    - V.G. Allfrey, M.M. Daly and A.E. Mirsky Some observations on protein metabolism in chromosomes of non-dividing cells, 1955 (Box 33)
      JGP 38, 415-424.
    - V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. On the supposed contamination of thymus nuclear fractions by whole cells, 1955 (Box 33)
      Science 121, 879-880.
    - V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. The Cell Nucleus. (A tentative outline for book), 1955? (Box 33)
      Typescript and handwritten outlines; photocopied writings by several authors.
    - V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. Synthesis of protein in the pancreas. III. Uptake of glycine-N15 by trypsinogen and chymotrypsinogen of mouse pancreas, 1955 (Box 33)
      JGP 39, 207-210.
      Typescript drafts with corrections.
    - V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky and S. Osawa Protein synthesis in isolated cell nuclei, 1955 (Box 33)
      Nature 176, 1042-1049.
      Correspondence; typescript draft.
    - A.E. Mirsky. The desoxyribonucleic acid content of animal cells and its evolutionary significance. Abstract. for Biological Abstracts, circa 1955 or 1956? (Box 33)
      (no further publication information).
      Typescript draft of abstract.
    - Miscellaneous (Not A.E. Mirsky), 1956? (Box 33)
      Possibly submitted to A.E. Mirsky because of references to Allfrey, Mirsky, Osawa work.
    - V.G. Allfrey, A.E. Mirsky and S. Osawa. Protein synthesis in isolated cell nuclei, 1957 (Box 33)
      JGP 40, 451-490.
      Galley proofs; typescript drafts of mss and abstract.
    - S. Osawa, A.E. Mirsky and V.G. Allfrey. Mononucleotides of the cell nucleus, 1957 (Box 33)
      JGP 40, 491-513.
      Galley proof; typescript drafts with corrections; photographs of figures and tables.
    - V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. The role of deoxyribonucleic acid and other polynucleotides in ATP synthesis by isolated cell nuclei, 1957 (Box 33)
      PNAS 43, 589-598.
      Correspondence; typescript draft and photograph of figure 1.
    - V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. Some effects of substituting the DNA of isolated nuclei with other polyelectrolytes, 1958 (Box 33)
      PNAS 44, 981-991.
      Typescript draft (page 1 missing); photograph of figures.
    - V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. Biochemical properties of the isolated nuclei, 1959 (Box 33)
      Subcellular Particles, American Physiological Soc, 186-207.
    - V.G. Allfrey and A.E. Mirsky. Contrasts in the metabolic stability of different nucleotides in the ribonucleic acids of isolated nuclei, 1959 (Box 33)
      PNAS 45, 1325-3344.
      Typescript draft; photographs of figures.